nationaljewelernetwork.com 2015-12-06

# Privacy Policy - National Jeweler

**EFFECTIVE DATE: February 1, 2015**

**Privacy Notice**  
This privacy notice covers the collection and use of information for this website (“website"). This website is managed and operated by National Jeweler, LLC (“National Jeweler” or “us” or “we”).

**About National Jeweler**  
Since 1906, National Jeweler has been a conduit to the largest and most actively engaged global community of jewelry industry professionals. We reach a highly targeted global network of jewelry retailers, designers, buyers, manufacturers, and suppliers through our comprehensive editorial coverage of the latest industry news and trends. National Jeweler reaches the U.S. industry's most important retailers, including every major reseller and virtually 100 percent of the companies listed as "1" or "2" operations by the Jewelers Board of Trade. The industry's only news analysis publication covers all the topics of importance to the retail community and is the leader in conducting and disseminating trade and consumer research and identifying the trends that shape the industry. [www.nationaljeweler.com](http://www.nationaljeweler.com/).

**What Information We Collect and How We Use It**  
We collect personally identifiable information that you choose to provide to us when you register for a trade show, subscribe to our magazines (either directly or through another company such as a subscription agency), sign up for email newsletters, enter a sweepstakes or contest, participate in surveys, or otherwise submit through our website. During the registration process we may request certain contact information and demographic information about you such as your name, mailing address, email address, company name, size of company and title. We also may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the information you have provided to us. If you choose to register for a trade show on this website, you may also be asked to provide your credit card information to fulfill your registration request.

**When We May Disclose Your Information to Others**  
National Jeweler may use and disclose your contact information for any of the following reasons:  
• To provide you with information about products or services you are interested in, including trade shows.  
• To provide you with e-newsletters you have requested.  
• To send you notices for subscription renewal.  
• To contact you regarding marketing endeavors.

If you do not wish to receive marketing information from National Jeweler, or wish to opt out of future email promotions from National Jeweler, please email [info@nationaljeweler.com](mailto:info@nationaljeweler.com). Please note that all promotional email messages you receive from National Jeweler will include an option to opt out of future email communications.

From time to time, National Jeweler may also share your contact information with other organizations, such as trade show exhibitors and vendors, for marketing purposes. If you do not wish to receive such offers, [please click here](http://o.emeraldexpoinfo.com/no.aspx).

We contract with third party companies that we have engaged to provide us with specialized services, including customer service, registration, subscription fulfillment, housing, research, statistical analysis, list cleansing, postal mailings, email and fax deployment, and other information services. These companies or individuals may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but only as needed to perform their functions. These companies are required to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of such information.

Notwithstanding any other provision of this privacy notice, we may disclose personally identifiable information to any third party when disclosure is required by law, or desirable to permit us to exercise or preserve our legal rights or take action regarding potentially illegal activities or to protect the safety of any person. In the event we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity or in the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Log Files**  
We may automatically collect non-personally identifiable information and data through the use of "cookies" or other technology. Cookies are small text files a website uses to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user's ongoing access to the website and facilitate the use of the website. Cookies and other technology also allow a website to track usage behavior and compile website usage information that will allow for the improvement of content and target advertising. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future.

We may also use third-party advertising companies, such as Google, to serve ads when you visit this website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (i.e., not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this website and other websites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/). Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality. The information collection and disclosure practices, and the choices that we provide to you, will continue to operate as described in this privacy notice, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received.

This website makes use of log files and collects information about your interaction with this website in order to perform analytics and market our services. This information may include your internet protocol (IP) address, associated company name, if any, browser type, platform, internet service provider (ISP), time and date stamp, general geographic information, referring pages and exit pages, or other non-personally identifiable information. We may use this information to gather additional information on website visitors, analyze trends and track a user’s path through the website, and/or improve the website’s performance. From time to time, we may also use this information to contact you for market research and sales purposes.

Google Analytics features on this website include Remarketing and Demographics & Interest Reporting:

**Children**  
This website is not directed at children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that this website has collected the personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact [info@nationaljeweler.com](mailto:info@nationaljeweler.com).

**Data Storage, Transfers, and Security**  
We may store the personal details we hold about you for as long as needed, which may be indefinitely. We may store this information in the United States or we may transfer it to any other country. If you are located outside of the United States and voluntarily submit personally identifiable information to us, you hereby consent to the use of such information as provided in this privacy notice and to the transfer of that information to and storage of that information in the United States. The data protection laws in countries to which personal data are transferred may or may not provide a level of protection equivalent to the laws in your home country. Wherever we hold the data, we will apply the terms of this privacy notice and any applicable data protection law. We maintain certain procedures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of personally identifiable information while it is controlled by us. However, the storage and communication of personal data cannot always be completely secure. Also, we cannot and do not guarantee that data transferred to third parties in accordance with this privacy notice will be protected against intentional or accidental misuse or loss.

**California Residents**  
California law permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [info@nationaljeweler.com](mailto:info@nationaljeweler.com) specifying that you seek your “California Customer Choice Notice” in the subject line.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**  
We may change this privacy notice and our data collection and management practices. We reserve the right to update changes to this privacy notice and to our practices in collecting and handling personally identifiable information. If we make material changes, we will post a notice at this website and indicate at the top of this statement when it was most recently updated.  
**Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this privacy notice applies.** You can reach us by sending an email to [info@nationaljeweler.com](mailto:info@nationaljeweler.com).
